<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on James Bland - DevOps Magic</title>
    <link>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on James Bland - DevOps Magic</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 09:57:50 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Fix Release and Deployment Pain</title>
      <link>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/fix-release-deployment-pain/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 09:57:50 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/fix-release-deployment-pain/</guid>
      <description>Regardless of the size of the organization, anyone who has done more than 2 releases or deployments knows about the pains involved. Sometimes the deployment fails right away and you spend hours trying to figure out the problem so you don’t have to roll back. Other times it’s a wakeup call at 2:00 AM to tell you the service is down. Regardless of how it happens, it’s always painful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monitoring, What to Monitor</title>
      <link>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/monitoring-what-to-monitor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 10:41:45 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/monitoring-what-to-monitor/</guid>
      <description>I seem to get this question a lot which tells me that there is still a lot of confusion about what to monitor, trend, and track for metrics. But it’s entirely understandable why there is confusion. We seem to have a proliferation of monitoring tools and with all their bells and whistles and it is easy to get lost in all the pretty graphs and charts. Most who ask the question are looking for a blueprint, but unfortunately it depends.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tools of the DevOps Trade - Source Code Control</title>
      <link>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/tools-of-the-devops-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jul 2019 10:35:01 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/tools-of-the-devops-trade/</guid>
      <description>Every trade and profession has its tools, DevOps is no different. In fact, the number of tools in the DevOps toolchain can be a bit overwhelming. I will try and break down some of the more popular toolsets and describe where they fit in the DevOps engineer arsenal. With this post, I will discuss source code control systems (SCCS).
Most people simply think that the only purpose of SCCS is to store source code for a software product that the company works on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Docker: The Ideal Tools Container</title>
      <link>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/docker-ideal-tools-container/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Jun 2019 10:26:35 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/docker-ideal-tools-container/</guid>
      <description>Besides the obvious use as a container for an application, docker works really well as a tools container that can be shared with developers, DevOps engineers, and operations folks. Just recently I was trying to share a bash wrapper script that I use to execute terraform with a windows developer and this effort quickly became an exercise in futility.
I didn’t have a lot of time so I told the developer to try Cygwin and see if it worked.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Batch Remove AWS Instances with Termination Protection Turned On</title>
      <link>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/batch-remove-aws-instances/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 09:42:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/batch-remove-aws-instances/</guid>
      <description>I recently got a request to terminate several hundred stopped instances on AWS. My first reaction was this is easy, just go into the GUI console, select all the instances and terminate. This could have been a solution if you have a few instances but selecting hundreds of instances intermingled between those needing termination and those that need to stay around is not exactly trivial. To add to the complexity, most of the instances that are targeted for termination had the termination protection flag turned on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a DevOps Engineer &amp; How Do I Become One</title>
      <link>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/what-is-a-devops-engineer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Jun 2019 10:14:59 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/what-is-a-devops-engineer/</guid>
      <description>Most people in the technology field has heard the word DevOps before, but base on my observations of how people describe it there seems to be a lot of confusion around what it actually is. If you ask a developer they will say an Ops guy and if you ask an Ops person they will say an automation person. Based on these vague descriptions no one really comes close to describing DevOps.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>LA DevOps Jobs Word Frequency Analysis (1 &amp; 2 words)</title>
      <link>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/la-devops-freq-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2019 10:45:04 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://jamesbland123.github.io/posts/la-devops-freq-analysis/</guid>
      <description>I decided to do an analysis of the LA DevOps jobs posted in the month of December 2018. The fist table is the top 2 word phrases filtered for stop phrases and company names of where I scaped the information. Some of the items are of no surpise, such as &amp;ldquo;DevOps Engineer&amp;rdquo;. The second table is unfiltered single word in the job postings.
What is interesting about this is that the first occurence of any technology or platform is AWS.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>